Brian E. Harding

(859) 536-2233 | 1421 Effingham St. Charlotte, NC 28208 | <u>brian.harding@gmail.com</u> <u>Github | Linkedin | Portfolio</u>

Professional Summary

Having worked in a variety of technology support roles in the higher education field for well over a decade I have the innate ability to pick up things quickly and move from one project to another with ease. As I transition my skills from support to building, I have poured my energy into learning new languages and frameworks to build exciting and robust applications.

Technical Skills

Node.js, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, GIT, Github, MySQL, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize, Google Places and Geocode API, Media Queries, APIs, JSON, REST, AJAX, the command line, computer science fundamentals, writing tests

Experience

Park Finder App

Collaborated with a team to develop a Javascript web application that pulls a user's location to determine the nearest list of public parks, as well as mapped results, using a variety of Google API's and storing results in a Firebase database for viewing and retrieval.

https://s-voss.github.io/nhs-mapper/index2.html

LIRI App

Web app used to search Twitter, OMDB, and Spotify API's for user results displaying song and movie title information in the Node environment.

https://github.com/bharding89/liri-node-app

Train Connector App

Calculates time for time imputed scheduling of theoretical trains in a Javascript and bootstrap front end, displaying updated minute by minute info via minute.js as well as a display of previous records stored in Firebase. https://bharding89.github.io/TrainTime/index.html

Employment

Darla Moore School of Business, University of South Carolina Multimedia Manager and Enterprise Video Systems Consultant Columbia, SC

November 2011 to February 2017

- Managed video streaming server systems live using Polycom CMA and RMX bridge as well as VOD with PRMM
- Designed instructions for use of video conference and classroom technologies by end users
- Monitored and setup of streaming classes, ensure recording was performed by Polycom and Adobe Connect systems
- Managed video streaming server systems both live and on-demand
- Connect video conferences for high level meetings for senior faculty using H323 and SIP

University of Kentucky

Lexington, KY

Multimedia Technology Specialist

August 2010 to November 2011

- Create and modify videos for streaming in online courses
- Train faculty with computer recording software and develop guide for use
- Lead project for bringing VOC Rehab online courses into ADA Compliance
- Design Excel/Access files for tracking progress of video recording schedule and online courses
- Support and maintain media on streaming server

Level 2 Helpdesk and Head Technical Support for Young Library Hub Project

2008 to August 2010

- Provide advanced support for students and staff computer accounts over email, phone, and walk-in
- Act as primary support for both W.T. Young library Hub location and Student Center Office

Level 1 Helpdesk Agent

July 2007 to August 2008

- Provide support for student and staff computer accounts, including Exchange, Microsoft, and Apple applications
- Accept email, phone, and walk-in technical support for faculty, staff, and students
- Track help desk requests using Remedy support system

Student and Temporary IT Consultant

February 2005 to July 2007

Teaching and Academic Support Center IT Center.

- Train clients with software and computer/multimedia equipment
- · Perform video editing and conversions using multiple software packages including Camtasia
- Organize and maintain content on DL Media Server

Brian E. Harding

(859) 536-2233 | 1421 Effingham St. Charlotte, NC 28208 | <u>brian.harding@gmail.com</u>
<u>Github</u> | <u>Linkedin</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

Education

University of North Carolina – Charlotte

Full Stack Web Development (Certificate)

Charlotte, NC
winter 2017

Midway College
Computer Information Systems Management (BA)
Midway, KY
2007 –2009

Bluegrass Community and Technical College

Computer Information Systems - Networking option (AS)

Lexington, KY
2004 - 2006

Volunteer, Special Projects, and Service Awards

ColaTown Bike Collective

Columbia, SC
Served as Secretary on board starting 2016

Columbia, SC
2014 to Current

- Collaborated with startup process, navigating and completing non-profit requirements, assembling board of directors.
- Responsible for meeting minutes of board, organizing and transposing, ensuring minutes are electronically available in a timely manner to all board members
- Participated in planning and execution of cycling events and classes
- Worked as mechanic and training of new volunteers on bicycle mechanics during weekends

Honorable Order of Kentucky Colonels, 2003

Awarded by Gov. Fletcher for outstanding community service to state of KY

Boy Scouts of America, 1995-2003

• Awarded Eagle Scout rank, 2003